A Guide to the Katie Letcher Lyle Papers, 1908-1986
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Katie Letcher Lyle Papers, 1908-1986
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9866-d
This collection contains ca. 1,500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift from Katie Letcher Lyle, Lexington, Virginia, on August 14, 1986.
Biographical/Historical Information
Katie Letcher Lyle is an American author.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains drafts, research material, correspondence, illustrations, and some copyright and financial material for two of Lyle's books: Scalded to Death by the Steam: Authentic Stories of Railroad Disasters and the Ballads That Were Written About Them and The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives: Being the Account of a Famous Murder Mystery of 1897 Supposedly Solved by the Testimony of a Ghost, Together with an Explanation of the Same.
Contents List
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., TMs (ec), pp. 31-167 (Box 1)
  W/ corrections
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., TMS (ec), pp. 234-270 (Box 1)
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  Captions w/ corrections
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., TMS (ec), pp. 168-275 (Box 1)
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  "Introduction" w/ source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1958-86, TMs, folder 1 of 2 (Box 1)
  "Old 97" w/ source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1958-86, TMs, folder 2 of 2 (Box 2)
  "Old 97" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1964-79, TMs (Box 2)
  "George Alley" or "The Wreck of the C & O" w/ source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., TMs (Box 2)
  "The N & W Cannonball Wreck" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1904, TMs (Box 2)
  "The New Market Wreck" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1911-83, TMs (Box 2)
  "Billy Richardson's Last Ride" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1911, AMs (Box 2)
  "The Hamlet Wreck" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1985, AMs (Box 2)
  "The Guyandotte Bridge Disaster" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1920-85, AMs (Box 2)
  "The Wreck of C & O #5" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1976, AMs (Box 2)
  "The Wreck of the 1256" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1982, TMs (Box 2)
  "The Church Hill Tunnel Disaster" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1925, 1961, TMs (Box 2)
  "The Freight Wreck at Altoona" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1926-76 (Box 2)
  "The Wreck of the Royal Palm" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1927-82, AMs (Box 2)
  "The Wreck of the Virginian Train #3" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1918-82, TMs (Box 3)
  "Three in Kentucky" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1930-78, TMs (Box 3)
  "The Wreck of the Sportsman" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  "Spikes on the Rail" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  Miscellaneous Subjects w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., AMs (Box 3)
  "The Bridge Was Burned at Chatsworth" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1979, AMs (Box 3)
  "Casey Jones" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1903, AMs (Box 3)
  "The Wreck of the Flyer Duquesne" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., AMs (Box 3)
  "The Maud Wreck" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1979-84, AMs (Box 3)
  "The Wreck of No. 3" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., AMs (Box 3)
  "The Nashville Wreck" w/source materials
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., AMs (Box 3)
  "The Ride to Hell" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d. (Box 3)
  "The Reckless Conductor" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., AMs, TMs (Box 3)
  "The Wreck of the 444" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., AMs (Box 3)
  "The Fate of Talmadge Osborne" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d. (Box 3)
  "The Wreck of Happy Valley" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., AMs, TMs (Box 3)
  "The Wreck of Old 85" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1982 (Box 3)
  "Ben Dewberry" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d. (Box 3)
  "John Henry" w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., AMs (Box 3)
  "Powellton"
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  Miscellaneous w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d. (Box 3)
  Non-Wrecks w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d. (Box 3)
  Bibliography w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d., ec (Box 3)
  Index w/ corrections
- Scalded to Death by the Steam n.d. (Box 3)
  Music w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1908-85, Folders 1 and 2 (Box 4)
  Graphics
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1982 (Box 4)
  Chronological List and Map w/source material
- Financial 1982 (Box 4)
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1983 (Box 4)
  Mailing List
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1982-86, Folders 1 and 2 (Box 4)
  Correspondence w/source material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1978-85, Folder 1 of 2 (Box 4)
  Correspondence
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1978-85, Folder 2 of 2 (Box 5)
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1978-85 (Box 5)
  Correspondence, Copyrights
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1971-85, Folders 1, 2, and 3 (Box 5)
  Miscellaneous Material
- Scalded to Death by the Steam 1981, 1983 (Box 5)
  Telephone Books w/source material
- Traveling Heritage Road 1969 (Box 5)
  Louise Rawl
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives n.d., TMs (Box 6)
  "Lucy" w/corrections
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1984, TMs (Box 6)
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives n.d., TMs (Box 6)
  W/corrections
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1984, TMs, pp. 10-102 (Box 6)
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1984, TMs (ec) (Box 6)
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1985, TMs (ec) (Box 6)
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1985, TMs (ec) (Box 6)
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1985, TMs (ec) (Box 7)
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1985, TMs (ec) (Box 7)
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1985, TMs (ec), folders 1 and 2 (Box 7)
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1985, TMs (ec), folders 1 and 2 (Box 7)
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1985 (Box 8)
  Area Map w/source material
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1983-84, TMs (Box 8)
  "Erasmus Stribling Trout Shue" w/ source material
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives n.d., TMs (Box 8)
  "Exhumation" w/corrections
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives n.d., TMs (Box 8)
  "Trial" w/ source material
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives n.d., TMs (Box 8)
  "Lynching" w/autograph corrections
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives n.d., TMs (Box 8)
  "The Artist" w/source material
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1985, TMs (ec) (Box 8)
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives n.d., TMs (ec) (Box 8)
  "Introduction" w/corrections
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives n.d., TMs (Box 8)
  And the Supporting Cast -- A. Jones, Rucker, Gardner, Preston, Knapp w/ source material
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives n.d. (Box 8)
  "Zona Heaster" w/source material
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1903-83, Folders 1 and 2 (Box 8)
  "Versions" w/source material
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1983-85 (Box 8)
  "Genealogy- Heaster/Shue" w/source material
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1978-85 (Box 8)
  W/source material
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1983-84 (Box 8)
  "Graphics" w/source material
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives n.d. (Box 8)
  "Ads" w/source material
- The Man Who Wanted Seven Wives 1983-85 (Box 8)